测试测试  一  二  三  测试
Testing. Testing. One. Two. Three. Testing.
见鬼
Damn it!
汉克  小心一些
Hank, careful with that, man.
抱歉  哥们
Sorry, man.
来了
Yo, here it is!
-什么  -昨晚演出的评论
- What? - The review from last night's show.
是好话吗
Do we want to hear it?
你喜欢别人说你是下个"涅槃乐队"吗
Only if you like being called the next Nirvana.
得了吧
Yeah, right.
哥们  他没开玩笑
Dude, he's not kidding.
圣夏普的转机已经到来
"Holy Shemp's future is now.
他们马上就要爆发了
They're about to explode,
就像主唱之一基斯·布鲁的标志性尖叫一样
just like one of singer Keith Blue's signature screams."
爽
Yeah!
听到了吗  我们火了  亲爱的
Did you hear that? We're taking off, baby!
詹姆斯在哪里  评论拿他和"锋利"做比较
Hey, hey, where's James? They're comparing him to The Edge.
他可能还在睡觉
Uh, he's probably still asleep.
咱们去把他叫醒
Let's go wake his ass up!
这是真的吗
Is this real?
吉米
Jimmy!
来吧  有好瞧的了
Come on. This is gonna be good.
醒醒  吉米  有摄像机来咯
Wakey, wakey, Jimbo. I'm coming in with a camera.
来吧
Come on.
进来
我真心希望他没像上次那样
I seriously hope his junk is not flapping in the breeze
还露着"鸟"
like last time.
快来
Come on.
救命  救命
Help! Help!
来人啊  来人啊
Help me! Help me!
莱恩  让他们别拍了
Ryan, get rid of the cameras.
好的  我来处理
Yeah, I'll take care of it.
警官  让这些摄像机别拍了
Hey, officer, we need to lose these cameras.
你知道规矩的  不许媒体采访
You know that. No press allowed.
他们不是媒体  他们好像在拍电影
Uh, they're not press. They're shooting some kind of movie.
他们在拍乐队的纪录片
No, they're--they're filming a documentary about the band.
你是哪位
And you are?
我是汉克·罗杰斯
I'm--I'm Hank Rogers.
我是乐队管理员之一
I'm one of the roadies.
-他认识被害人  -好的
- He knew the victim. - All right.
你得录份口供
Well, I'm gonna need a statement, okay?
开什么玩笑  这里也在拍
Are you kidding me? They're in here, too?
我要求他们离开
I asked them to leave,
但他说导演让他全拍下来
but he said that the director told him to shoot all this.
你是不是想让自己的镜头开花啊
How'd you like to try to film with a cracked lens, huh?
好了
All right.
埃斯波  去找导演
Espo, just go get their director.
让他叫摄像队离开
Tell him to get the crew out of here.
埃斯波西托
Hey, Esposito.
看来某人还没喝到咖啡啊
Someone didn't get their coffee.
这怎么回事
What's this?
他们在拍乐队的纪录片
They are making a documentary on the band.
无视他们就行了
Yeah, just ignore 'em.
理查德·卡塞尔  小说家
Richard Castle, novelist.
我最新的力作  《冰冻希特》已经上市
My latest, "Frozen Heat," in stores now.
你见过妮基·希特的原型了吗
Have you met, uh, Nikki Heat's inspiration--
就是这位贝克特探长
Detective Beckett?
蕾妮  还有什么发现
Lanie, what else do we know?
死者是詹姆斯·斯旺
Victim is James Swan.
圣夏普的主吉他手
He's the lead guitarist of Holy Shemp.
他们肯定是"活宝三人组"的粉丝
They must be Three Stooges fans.
据尸斑来看
Based on lividity,
死亡时间应该是在午夜至凌晨两点
I'd say the time of death is between 12:00 and 2:00 a.m.
看这个
Look at that.
观察
"Observe."
被忽视的警惕信号
An unheeded call to vigilance.
那是凶器
So that's the murder weapon.
那是吉普森公司出品的莱斯·保罗型吉他
It's a Gibson Les Paul.
59年火焰纹面板  如果我没错的话
59 flame top if I'm not mistaken,
而我几乎不会犯错
and I'm rarely mistaken.
好烫
That's hot.
跟我说说这把吉他
Tell me about this guitar.
火焰纹面板是他最喜欢的
Well, the flame top is his favorite.
昨晚演出结束后
Uh, last night after the show,
我给吉他调了音  放在了他的拖车里
I tuned it and I dropped it off at his trailer.
他喜欢用这个来作曲
He likes to compose on it.
好的  那时候几点
All right. Uh, what time was that at?
大概11点30
It was around 11:30.
好的  他那时候一个人吗
All right. Was, uh, he alone at the time?
是的
Yeah. Yeah.
我们聊了一会儿
We chatted for a second.
他一直对我很客气
He's always really nice to me.
他只关心音乐
It was all about the music with him.
当时拖车外有人吗
Was there, uh, anyone hanging outside the trailer,
有没有你不认识的人
Maybe someone you didn't recognize?
我看到一辆白色货车
I saw a white van.
在街上开来开去几次
It went around the block a couple of times.
有看到车牌号吗
Oh, did you get a plate number?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
当时太黑了
It was dark.
好的  别走开
All right. Um, don't go anywhere.
是  不  我...
Yeah. No, I--
你不能撤资
You can't pull your funding.
喂  你是导演吗
Yo. You the director?
是  不行
Yeah. Yeah, no.
听着  这个肯定赚钱  明白吗
You--look, we are sitting on gold here. Okay?
这可是包含了摇滚乐队纪录片和...
This is part rock doc part, uh--
这里是犯罪现场
This is a crime scene.
你得叫摄像队出去
You gotta get these cameras outta here.
好的
All right.
我得挂了
Look, I-I gotta go.
如果你能拿到  就打我电话
Just call me if--if you can get that thing.
你得帮帮忙
Look, you gotta help me out here, okay?
我已经没日没夜地跟着他们三个月了
I-I've been following these guys nonstop for three months.
立刻停止  警察办案  抱歉
Not anymore. Police procedure. Sorry.
如果你每天24小时盯着死者
And if you've been following the victim 24/7,
我需要看那些影带
I'm gonna need to see that footage.
听我说  探长
Look, detective.
我现在很为难
Look... I'm in a spot here.
詹姆斯·斯旺
Okay, James Swan...
是乐队的灵魂
Was that band.
他死了  就没人会在乎其他成员
With him gone, no one is gonna care about these guys
也不会想看这部电影
or want to see this film.
除非我把电影改成惊悚片之类的
So unless I can reinvent it as some kind of thriller,
拍成缉凶纪录片
you know, a hunt for the murderer--
人们可喜欢看这些了
People love that stuff.
听我说  这里有人死了
Listen to me, a guy's dead here.
如果你不让这些摄像队离开
So if you don't get rid of these cameras,
我就打烂你的...
I'm gonna break one over your--
等一下  抱歉  说吧
One second. Sorry. Yeah, go ahead.
太好了
Oh, great.
等等
Okay, hang on.
我把电话给警探
I'm gonna give you to a detective.
喂
Hello.
这是冲动犯罪
This was a crime of passion.
双方发生争执  事件升级
There was an argument, things got heated,
凶手抓过最近的重物
the killer grabbed the nearest heavy object,
打倒了可怜的斯旺先生
and felled poor mr. Swan
真是悲剧  他还如此年轻
at the tragically young age of...
他多大了
How old was he?
27岁
27.
哇  俱乐部的又一员
Wow. Another one for the club.
什么俱乐部
What club?
27岁俱乐部
The 27 club.
会员有很多大人物
Memberships include some of the greats--
吉米·亨德里克斯  吉姆·莫里森
Jimi Hendrix, Jim Morrison,
詹尼斯·乔普林
Janis Joplin.
名单还很长
The list is extensive.
卡塞尔  我们需要的是另一份名单
Castle, we kind of need a different list,
比如谁可能昨晚上过这辆拖车
like who might have been in this trailer last night.
我知道从哪里入手了
I think I know where to start.
蕾妮
Lanie.
走走走  出去
Go, go, go, go. Get outta here.
天呐  谢谢
oh, my god. Thank you.
他简直是个天才
The guy was a total genius.
我追随了乐队六个月
I followed the band for six months
就是为了见他
trying to meet him.
几周前  我和詹姆斯在一起了
A couple weeks ago, James and I got together,
从那晚起
And evernight since,
表演一结束我就去他的拖车见他
I'd meet him in his trailer right after the show.
那事发当时你在拖车里
So you were in his trailer when it happened?
我想是吧
I guess. I mean, I, um,
我什么都不记得了
I-I don't remember anything.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你怎么会不记得
How can you not remember?
我昏睡过去了
I passed out.
我想我...
I guess I...
演出时有点嗨过头了
partied a little too hard during the show.
抱歉  我也想帮忙
I'm sorry. I want to help.
-听着  怎么称呼  -小蝴蝶
- Listen, miss... - Butterfly.
小蝴蝶  事关重大
Butterfly, this is very important.
你还记得当晚发生过的事吗
Do you remember anything about that night?
什么都行
Anything at all?
在他的拖车里
In his trailer...
我听到了马的声音
I heard a horse.
马嘶声吗
A horse as in whinnying?
不是
No.
我听到了马蹄声
I heard the sound of horse hooves
在雪地里咯吱作响
Crunching in the snow.
像是  咯吱  咯吱  咯吱
Like, crunch, crunch, crunch--
好  能不能只讲你昏睡过去前
Okay, can we, uh, just focus on what happened
发生的事
just before you passed out?
他看上去有什么心事吗
Did he seem like he was upset?
他有没有像是和人争吵过
Did he seem like he had been fighting with anyone?
实际上正相反
Actually, the opposite.
他最近常在抱怨
He'd been complaining a lot
乐队其他几个人的事
about the other guys in the band recently,
他们会有争论  关系紧张
you know, the--the arguments and the tension.
可昨晚
but last night,
他好像很开心
he--he seemed happy, you know?
就像找到了某种安宁
Like--like he'd found some kind of peace.
我不知道那姑娘会不会有足够的力气
I don't know if that girl could swing a guitar
挥起吉他杀人
with enough force to kill anyone,
可我还是得检查她的衣物寻找血渍
but I still gotta check her clothes for blood spatter.
我对那些乐队成员的争端
I'm more interested in what the band members
更感兴趣
were fighting about.
你们在干什么
Hey, what are you guys doing here? Huh?
马上出去  我们在调查凶案
Get outta here now. This is a police investigation.
你们无权来这里
You have no right to be here.
实际上  你说错了
Uh, actually, that's not true.
抱歉  探长  但我也束手无策
I'm sorry, detective, but it's out of my hands.
市政厅认为这样有助公关
City hall has decided it's good P.R.
等等  那案子呢
Wait. What about the case?
他们会影响调查...
They're gonna compromise the investig--
我也有同感
I feel the same way as you do,
可他们已经做了决定
but a decision has been made,
我希望你能照做
and I expect you to comply with it.
好  那让他们别干扰我做事
Fine. Then just have them stay out of my way.
你好  欢迎光临
Hi. Uh... Welcome.
我是盖茨警监
I'm Captain Gates,
第12分局的头儿
head of the 12th Precinct.
配合纽约警局的公共事务部门
In cooperation with the NYPD's public affairs division,
我很高兴为你们放开警局的一切权限
I am happy to grant you full access to the department.
你会发现这里所有人
I think you will find everyone here
都热情好客
more than accommodating.
欢迎
Welcome.
拜托  有什么大不了的
Come on. What's the big deal?
会很有意思
It'll be fun.
听着  卡塞尔  我在这做的事是我的事
Look, Castle, what I do here, this is... mine.
而只因为他们想侵犯我的隐私
And just because they want to invade my privacy,
不代表我就得推波助澜
it doesn't mean that I have to help them do it.
好吧  或许吧
Okay. Well, that may be.
可这些摄像头要缠着我们了
But... these cameras, they're not going anywhere.
他们会拍到些东西
They're gonna see something.
我只想让他们看到我看到的
I just want them to see what I see.
等等  为什么需要我们的不在场证明
Hold on. Why do you need our alibis?
因为我们了解到斯旺先生和乐队的关系
Because we understand that there was some tension
有点紧张
between Mr. Swan and the band.
关系紧张多正常啊
Of course there was tension.
我们朝夕相处  总会有点摩擦
You spend every second together, it's not always gonna be pretty.
我们组团五年了
We've been together for five years.
如果你知道想在这行做得好
Like, if you had any idea the kind of crap
都要承受些什么压力...
that you go through trying to make it in this business...
这种压力会让人很团结
It has a way of bonding people.
要不就使他们非常非常厌恶彼此
Or making them really, really sick of each other.
我们很照顾詹姆斯
Hey, we looked out for James.
他是来自俄亥俄州的中产阶级孩子
He was a middle-class kid from Ohio.
他根本不了解这种生活
He didn't know what the hell he was getting into with this life.
我们还是需要关于你们
Yeah. Well, we're still gonna need statements
昨晚去向的口供
about where you were last night.
好吧  我在我的拖车里
Fine. I was in my trailer.
-表演结束我就去了  -我也是
- I went there right after the show. - Me, too.
我们都在自己的拖车里
We were all in our trailers.
我们有记录显示
All right, well, we have reports
那一带有辆白色面包车
that there was a white van in the area.
詹姆斯有没有提到过
Did James ever mention anything about that?
没
No.
不过他确实认为有人跟踪他
But he did think someone was following him.
对  一个月前
Yeah, uh, it was a month ago.
就在我们去伊萨卡的那段时间
Right around the time we played Ithaca.
他疑神疑鬼的
He w--he was acting all paranoid.
他说要多雇些保安
He was talking about hiring extra security.
他说他怕谁了吗
Did he say who he was afraid of?
没  可他最近没提这事了
No, but, um, he hadn't brought it up recently,
所以我以为一切回归正常了
so I just assumed everything was normal
-直到他昨晚闹了那一出  -对
- until he pulled that stunt yesterday. - Yeah.
昨天怎么了
What happened yesterday?
他没参加我们一点的乐队会议
He blew off our 1:00 band meeting.
我们六点校音时才见到他
We didn't see him again until sound check at 6:00.
他从没缺席过乐队会议
The guy never missed a band meeting.
他说去哪里了吗
Did he say where he was going?
没说
No.
不过我知道
But I do know this,
一直追拍他的摄像师
the camera guy that was following him
说詹姆斯故意把他甩开了
said that James ditched him on purpose.
所以不管他在做什么  都不想让人知道
So whatever he was doing, he didn't want anyone to know.
喂  你们有时间吗
Yo. You guys got a sec?
我翻看了
so, uh, I've been going through
死者生前的纪录片
the documentary footage of our victim.
看这个
Check this out.
大部分人会说
Most guys will tell you that
他们是自学的吉他
they, uh, they learned to play guitar themselves.
但我有个导师
But I had a mentor.
他十分了不起
And... And the guy was incredible.
我永远达不到他的高度
You--much better than I'll ever be.
他怎么看乐队的
What's he think of the band?
我们很久没联络了
You know, we lost touch a ways back.
在那里  看到了吗
There. You see that guy?
这段录像拍摄于一个月前
That was taken over a month ago.
而这些...
These...
是更近期的
are more recent.
好吧
All right.
往后退一点
B-- just move back a bit.
好了
There we go.
这里  这里
Boom. Boom.
看来他一直在跟踪被害人
Yeah, it looks like our vic had a stalker.
看看这张
Check out this one.
这张是昨天拍到的
This is from yesterday.
看他倚在什么上面
Look what he's leaning against.
白色货车
A white van.
我们抓到你了  你个狗娘养的
We've got you now, you son of a bitch.
抱歉  我可以说狗娘养的吗
I'm sorry. Can I even say son of a--
我们把白色货车的图片放大
So we blew up the picture of the white van
直到能看得清牌照
wide enough to get a license plate.
它的注册地址就在这附近
It's registered to an address somewhere around here.
在前面往右转
Make a right up ahead.
不  我要走另一条路
No, I'm going another way.
你什么意思  只有一条路
What do you mean? There's only one way.
不  还有一条路  在后面有条路
No, there's a different way. There's a back way.
后面才没有路呢
There's no back way.
相信我  相信我
Trust me. Trust me.
请不要误会
I-I know how this might look,
我们其实是很不错的搭档
but we actually make a pretty good team
我们各有不同的特长
because we each have, uh, different strengths.
没错
That's true.
比如  我以前是军人
For example, I'm former military,
所以我是个神枪手
which makes me an expert marksman.
我通常是第一个破门而入的
I'm usually first through the door.
是啊  但总得有人知道该冲向哪扇门
Well, yeah, but somebody's gotta know which door to go through.
而我则比我的搭档  要细心慎重得多
I'm a little bit more, um, circumspect, uh, than my partner here.
我就像是团队的神经中枢
I'm kinda like the--the nerve center of the team.
而我则是身强体壮的那位
But I'm definitely the physical one.
我身体一直很棒
I stay in sick shape.
瞧瞧  见过这么健壮的二头肌吗
Boom. Have you been to the gun show?
我开玩笑的
I'm just kidding.
我只是  说真的  我身体很棒
I'm just--seriously, though, I'm in sick shape.
老兄  你这衬衫是怎么回事
Dude, what's with the shirt?
很紧啊  你换衣服了吗
It's really tight. Did you change it?
我  洒了些东西在上面
I... I spilled something on it.
到了
Ah, here it is.
缓慢接近
Slow approach.
跟紧点
Stay close.
我觉得他看到我们了
I think he saw us.
我来
I got this.
看一下他的货车吧
Let's go check out the van.
瞧瞧我们找到了什么
What do we have here?
我很确定那不是番茄酱
Pretty sure that ain't ketchup.
那就是我们要找的跟踪狂吗
Hey, is that our stalker?
前跟踪狂
Ex-stalker.
他很快就将过上不见天日的生活了
He won't be seeing daylight any time soon.
LT  你能带他到审讯室吗  谢谢
L.T., could you please take him to an interrogation room? Thank you.
你去观察室旁观吧  我来攻破他
You should watch from observation while I tear this guy apart.
他有什么可疑之处吗
So, uh, we like this guy?
我们在他的车上发现血滴
We found bloodstained overalls in his van.
已经送去化验室
We sent 'em to be tested
看看是否和被害人的血样吻合
to see if they match the blood from our vic.
肯定吻合  相信我  老兄
Oh, they match. Trust me, bro.
你们不用再担心这个变态
You won't have to worry about this creep
再出去伤害别人了
hurting anyone ever again.
那是我送给你的礼物
That's a gift from me to you.
别客气  祖国母亲
You're welcome, America.
我错过什么了吗
I miss anything?
没有  他们才刚开始
No. They're just getting started.
绳子  汽油
Rope,gasoline.
你对詹姆斯·斯旺心存歹心
You wanted to do nasty things to James Swan.
我不知道你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我觉得你清楚得很
Oh, I think you do.
我给你一点时间
I'm gonna give you a second...
把情况理清楚
to get your facts straight.
哇  限定时间  真是经典手段
Ooh, the time-out. That's a classic.
审讯  其实也是一种艺术
Interrogation, it's really an art form.
比如  贝克特探长  就是一位大师
I mean, detective Beckett here, she is a master.
我见过她在这间小屋子里破获无数起案件
I have watched her crack countless cases in this very room.
你记得那个杀害自己园丁的男人吗
You remember that guy who killed his gardener
就因为他把玫瑰剪得太短
because he cut his roses too short?
我们找到了你的工作裤
Found your overalls.
上面都是斯旺的血
They had Swan's blood all over 'em.
那不是他的血  是我自己的血
It's not his blood. It's my blood.
我在车上弄东西时  不小心割伤了
I cut myself when I was working on my van.
别瞎编了  乔  你以为我们蠢吗
Oh, come on, Joe. What, do you think we're stupid?
我们有录像证明你跟踪他好几周
We've got you on video following him for weeks.
我们发现你的车出现在案发现场
We've got your van at the crime scene.
你就别再装清白了好吗
So why don't you cut the innocent crapright now!
你想让我承认吗  那我就承认吧
You want me to admit it? I admit it.
我是跟踪他  我承认
I followed him. I did.
我只是打算抓住他
I was just planning to grab him.
但是你的计划出了差池
And that's when your plan went sideways.
你想将他拖到你的车上
you tried to drag him to your van,
但是他不愿意
but he didn't want to go.
不是那样的
That's not how it happened.
-然后你怒火中烧  -不是那样的
- And that's when you got mad-- - That's not how it happened!
然后你怒火中烧
That's when you got mad
然后你敲碎了他的脑袋
And that's when you busted his head open.
我没有杀人
I didn't kill anybody.
我只是
I just...
我只是想找回我闺女
I just want my little girl.
你闺女
Your little girl?
我女儿
My daughter.
她辞了工作  成了粉丝
She quit her job to become a groupie.
完全抛弃了人生
Threw her whole life away.
我很担心她被搞大肚子
I was afraid she was gonna get pregnant...
或者更糟
Or worse.
我只想抓住他
All I wanted to do was grab him.
我想吓唬吓唬他
I wanted to scare him a little.
我想让他离她远一点
I wanted him to stay away from her.
你女儿
Your daughter?
是的
Yes.
我已经好几周没见过她了
I haven't seen her in weeks.
我都不知道她是否还活着
I don't even know if she's alive.
她的名字是不是叫小蝴蝶
Does she go by the name of Butterfly?
是的
Yes.
我觉得我们可以帮你找到她
I think we can help you find her,
如果我的搭档没意见的话
If it's okay with my partner.
似乎那个跟踪狂说的是实话
Well, looks like our stalker was telling the truth.
初步化验结果表明工装裤上的血是他自己的
Prelim shows that the blood on his overalls was his.
我很遗憾  搭档
Sorry, partner.
至少抓住那家伙也不算是彻头彻尾的失败
Well, at least grabbing the guy up wasn't a total bust.
我可不觉得  似乎就是彻头彻尾的失败嘛
I don't know. It seems to be the definition of a total bust.
如果我刚刚没在拘留室继续问话  那确实如此
Well, it would've been if hadn't just spoken to him in holding.
既然他一直尾随着被害人
Seeing as how he was tailing our victim,
他很清楚斯旺被害那天下午去了哪里
He knew exactly where Swan Was on the afternoon of his death.
很好  哪里
Great. Where?
他先是去了苏豪区的一家银行  然后去了
He was at a bank in soho and then he went into
拉斐特街和布鲁姆街交汇路口的一幢居民楼
a residential building on the corner of Lafayette and Broome.
去那里做什么
Yes, but why?
斯旺甩掉了摄影师  自己悄悄地去办事
Swan eluded his cameraman to go on a clandestine errand,
此事如此重要  以至于他缺席了乐队会议
an errand so important, he missed a band meeting.
他的行程并不规律  在那之前去了趟银行
He was acting erratically, went to the bank right beforehand.
这些线索都指向一件事
This all points to one thing.
-毒品  -毒品
- Drugs. - Dr-drugs.
推论挺有意思  但这完全是猜测
That's an interesting theory, but that is pure speculation.
其实不然
Actually, it's not.
要让我猜测的话  我会说斯旺购买了
Pure speculation would be Swan purchasing
热核技术产品
thermonuclear technology
让科学家给他做个扩音器
to have a scientist make him an amplifier
让12区都能听见他的声音
that went all the way to 12.
而这个
This...
音乐家买毒品
Musicians buying drugs--
那可真是家常便饭
That's just Monday morning crossword.
我去查查房客  看有没有可疑的
I'll pull a list of tenants, see if anyone pops.
蕾妮有东西要给我们看
Lanie's got something she wants us to see.
蕾妮  蕾妮是谁
Lanie. Who's Lanie?
蕾妮是我们的法医
Uh, Lanie is our medical examiner.
她在停尸房工作
And she works at the morgue.
她有线索要给我们看
And she's got information that she wants us to see,
而我们在让她干等着
and we are keeping her waiting.
-还是有点僵硬  -确实  她总是太严肃
- Still a little stiff. - Certainly, she could tighten that up,
不过已经好多了
but she's getting better.
死者的血液测试报告出来了
The victim's blood panels came back.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
有毒品
Drugs.
不  他可真是难得安分守己的摇滚明星
Nope. This was one clean-living rock star.
事实上  他体内有什么并不重要
In fact, it's not what he put in his body,
重要的是他缺的东西
it's what he didn't.
詹姆斯体内没有小儿麻痹症抗体
James had no antibodies for polio.
他从没注射过小儿麻痹症疫苗吗
He never had the polio vaccine?
等一下  20世纪60年代后出生的人
Wait. Everyone born since the early 1960s
都打过那个疫苗
got that vaccine.
我也在琢磨这事
That's what I thought.
他体内也没有破伤风疫苗  麻疹疫苗
He also had no antibodies for tetanus, measles,
百日咳疫苗  各种标准疫苗都没
whooping cough-- all standard immunizations.
还有什么
What else?
这还不够吗
Isn't that enough?
蕾妮  你通常有这种线索时
Lanie, usually if you have something like this for me,
都只是用电话通知我
you just call me over the phone.
我觉得你们该过来跑一趟
Well, I thought it was worth the trip.
莱恩  查一下死者的医疗记录
Ryan, can you look into our vic's medical records?
我想知道他为何从没接种过疫苗
I wanna find out why he was never vaccinated.
这就去
On it.
我想我搞清楚
Okay, I think I figured out
詹姆斯·斯旺为什么去那幢楼了
why James Swan went to that building.
他有个熟人住那里  叫山姆·斯比尔
He knew a guy who lived there-- a Sam Spear.
那家伙在跟我们的死者打个大官司
Dude has an outstanding lawsuit against our vic.
什么官司
What kind of a lawsuit?
他告詹姆斯
Well, he claims that James
盗取了一首他给乐队写的歌的版权
stole one of the band's songs from him,
詹姆斯肯定是觉得理亏
and James must have thought he had a case,
因为他在见山姆之前去了银行
because when he stopped at a bank on his way to see this guy,
取走了两万五千美元的现金
he took out 25 grand, cash.
看来他是想庭外和解
Sounds like he's trying to settle out of court.
对  而且我猜他没有成功
Yeah, and I'm guessing it didn't pan out.
山姆·斯比尔买了一张昨晚演出的门票
Sam Spear bought a ticket to last night's show.
也就是说在斯旺被害前他就在剧院
So he was at the theater right before Swan was killed.
该去找这人谈谈了
Time to pay this guy a visit.
不不不  这个我负责
No. No, no, no. I got this.
你就在这儿做你的小研究吧
You stay here and work on your little research project,
脑力活可都得靠你
you being the nerve center and all.
卡塞尔
Castle.
你去吧
Uh, you coming?
不了
No, I'm good.
等等我
Wait up.
不是这间
It's not this one.
斯比尔住在3M号房
Spear's in 3-M.
贝克特探长并不是个不友好的人
You know, Detective Beckett is not an unfriendly person.
她只是比较戒备
She's just got walls.
怎么说呢  就是她有许多层
Let's-- let's call them layers.
一层一层的戒备
Layers upon layers of uh, well, walls.
但一旦你打破了这些戒备
But once you scale those walls...
就会像雨过天晴一般
the effort is worth it.
卡塞尔  请你小点声
Castle. Keep your voice down, please.
我今天已经拷过一个人了
All right. I've already had one guy bolt on me today.
关键是突然袭击  看  我也能很细心的
Element of surprise is key. See, I can be circumspect.
伙计们没我可不行
Folks would be lost without me.
他走错方向了
He went the wrong way.
是3M  斯比尔家
It's 3-M. Spear's place.
-放下武器  -准备好了吗
- Drop your weapon! - You ready?
快点把她放开
Let her go right now...
纽约警局  都不许动
NYPD! Nobody moves!
-举起双手  -好好
- Get your hands up! - Yeah. Oh, yeah, yeah.
举起手来
Let me see your hands!
怎么回事
What is this?
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
一部烂片罢了
It's just a bad movie.
我在谱曲
I'm just composing the score.
这完全是个误会
This is all a misunderstanding.
我们来回顾一下
Let's review--
您告詹姆斯·斯旺偷了你一首歌
You sued James Swan over a song,
昨天他因此事来找过你
and then he came to see you about it yesterday.
几小时后  他在演出完毕后遇害
A few hours later, he was killed right after his show.
-什么  -而且你还去现场观看了演出
- What? - A show that you attended.
但我们都协商好了
But we worked all that out.
我  他会把那首歌一半的发行收益分给我
I--he was gonna give me half the publishing for that song.
一旦合同签订
I was gonna drop the complaint
我立马就会撤销诉讼了
as soon as the papers were signed.
那他给你的两万五千美金怎么解释
That doesn't explain the 25 grand he brought to you.
两万五  那可不关我的事
25--I-I-I don't know anything about that.
他希望我为他写歌
Look, he wanted me to write for him.
现在工作这么难找  杀死老板也太蠢了吧
It'd be pretty stupid to kill off an employer in this job market.
你在给他写歌
You were writing songs for him?
对  这里  看
Uh, yeah. Here. Uh, look.
我已经开始了
I-I already started.
这首都写了好多了
I got pretty far on that one.
我看看
Let me see that.
和声部分确实不错
I do like the vocal line on this.
你看的懂乐谱
You read music?
怎么  我是个警察  就不能会唱歌了吗
What, you think, because I'm a cop, I can't sing?
不  我认为你不会唱歌是因为我听过你唱歌
No, I think you can't sing because I've heard you sing.
那个卡拉OK机有问题
That karaoke machine was busted.
回头我唱给你听
I'm gonna sing for y'all later.
如果只是找人写歌
If this was just about writing songs,
为什么要这么神神秘秘
why all the secrecy?
他没说出口  但我猜测过
He never said, but I had my theories,
因为他乐队的新成员
especially because this new stuff
在音乐能力上与他差距太大
was such a musical departure for him,
我相信你们也注意到了
as I'm sure you noticed.
是啊  稍等一下
Yeah--just one sec.
他想改变音乐风格
Taking the music in a new direction,
但又不想乐队的其他人知道
but he didn't want the rest of the band to know.
就是这样
Of course.
斯旺准备单飞了
Swan was going solo.
这假设合理
Makes sense.
导演说斯旺是整个团队的
The director said that Swan was the creative force
创作来源
behind the group,
如果他要单飞  乐队就完蛋了
That if he left the band, they would flounder.
如果有一个队员发现了
What if one of the other members found out
当面和他对质呢
and confronted him?
他们争吵  事情越闹越糟糕
And they argued, and things got ugly.
没错  他无意继续留队
Right. He wasn't about to stay.
他们也不会让他像乔治·迈克尔那样
And they weren't about to let him play George Michael
离开安德鲁·维治利
to their Andrew Ridgeley.
-安德鲁谁  -没错
- Andrew who? - Exactly.
所以他们拿起一把吉他...
So they pick up a guitar...
然后  "威猛"
And Wham!
我就是干这个的
It's what I do.
不赖
That's not bad.
-很有表现力  -是
- It gives it weight. - Yeah.
找了新吉他手
Got yourself a new guitarist.
换人试试呗
Trying someone out, yeah.
速度挺快嘛
Well, that was fast.
不过我猜这次试演
Though I guess you had this audition
是你提前就安排好的吧
lined up already, didn't you?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
得了吧  基斯
Come on, Keith.
你早知道詹姆斯要单飞
You knew James was going solo.
是真的吗  哥们儿
Is that true, man?
不  当然不是  我怎么会知道
No, of course not. How would I know that?
我们在唱片公司遇到一个女孩
We met with a woman from the record label.
她说她是你的女朋友
She says that she's your girlfriend.
她说她曾和詹姆斯有过接触
She said that she had a meeting on the books
说他想要有所改变
with James about making some changes
同时还有传言说他要离开乐队
and that there were rumors that he wanted to leave the band.
那么多年  你们一起并肩努力
All those years, struggling side by side.
而今成功唾手可得
And now success finally at hand,
他却想独占所有的荣誉
he wanted to take all the glory for himself.
要是我  我也会发怒
I know I'd be mad.
我不能就站在这儿  任你们污蔑我
I'm not gonna stand here and let you accuse me
杀害了我最好的朋友
of killing one of my best friends, all right?
你听到那声音了吗
You hear that sound?
有点像马蹄踩踏在雪地里的嘎吱声
Kind of like horse hooves crunching on snow?
就像小蝴蝶在斯旺拖车上听到的声音
Just like what Butterfly heard in Swan's trailer.
听着  我们知道他心里窝火
Look, we know he's got a temper,
如果我们能够激怒他
so if we can get him angry enough--
事实上  你何不独自审问基斯呢
Actually, why don't you talk to Keith yourself?
为什么
Why?
因为我想给你点空间
Because I want to give you room to operate
好让你发挥
and strut your stuff.
妥妥的
You got this.
She's got this.
不是吧  这你也得录下来吗
Really, you gotta film this, too?
他们想拍什么就拍什么  基斯
They can film whatever they want, Keith.
是你自己签的字
You signed a release.
你杀詹姆斯·斯旺的时候摄像机没开着
You're lucky the cameras weren't rolling
就算你走运了
when you killed James Swan.
听着  我已经说过了  我没杀他
Look, I already said, I didn't kill him.
是啊  你还说过
Yeah, and you also said
你并不知道他要单飞
that you didn't know that he was going solo
演出结束后也没见过他
and that you didn't see him after the show,
但我有证人能证明你在案发当时
But I have a witness that places you in his trailer
就在他的拖车里
at the time of death.
听着  我是去过他的拖车
All right, look, I did go to his trailer. Okay?
但也正如你说的
But it was like you said.
我听到了他要单飞的传言
I heard rumors that he was cutting out on us.
我去证实下是不是真的
I went to see if it was true.
然后你失去了控制
And then after that, you lost control.
不  我们只是谈了谈  行吗
No, we just talked. Okay?
而且詹姆斯否认了  他说他没有要离开
And James denied it. He said that he wasn't leaving.
他说他正在处理些事
He said he was working out something
对我们乐队有好处
that'd be good for all of us.
他到底在处理什么事
And what exactly was this something?
听着  我曾经一直以为我了解他
Look, I used to think I knew that dude,
但他自从伊萨卡回来后就不一样了
but he hasn't been the same since Ithaca.
我告诉你  那里一定发生过什么
I am telling you, something happened there.
基斯  我没说伊萨卡
Keith, I'm not talking about Ithaca.
我说的是在拖车里到底发生了什么
I am talking about what happened in that trailer.
我们聊了会  我走了
We talked. I left.
之后整晚我都待在我的拖车里
I went back to my trailer for the rest of the night.
我和一个姑娘在一起  你可以问她
I was with this girl. You can ask her.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
我不记得
I don't remember her name.
那电话号码呢
A phone number then?
任何我能找到她的东西
Anything so I can get ahold of her?
她们都是主动上门
They come to me.
基斯  你可得好好想清楚
Keith, you're gonna have to do a lot better than that.
行  好吧
Okay. All right.
我不记得她的名字
I may not remember her name...
但我能证明我们那晚在一起
but I can prove that we were together that night.
得  他俩真在一起
Well, they were together, all right.
汤米·李都比不上这家伙
Tommy Lee's got nothing on this guy.
我喜欢时不时地来跟进监督一下案子
I like to check on the case every once in a while.
当大家都在这里奋斗的时候
No point in chaining myself to that desk
我可完全没必要把自己栓在办公桌前
when all the action is right out here.
想要行动  看这里
You want action, check this.
喂喂喂  等等
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
这是不正当的办公室行为
This is inappropriate workplace behavior.
这是证据  长官
This is evidence, sir.
我们嫌疑人的不在场证明就靠它了
Our suspect's alibi hinges on this.
原来如此
Oh. Oh.
他的故事有结果了吗
So does his story pan out?
是  看来整个死亡时间区
Yeah, it seems like he's covered
他都有不在场证明
for the entire time-of-death window.
但愿你没有轻信视频里的时间标记吧
I hope you're not going on the time stamp on this video.
知道吗  这个是可以伪造的
That could be faked, you know?
这不是视频里唯一伪造的东西
That's not the only thing on this video being faked.
背景里有电视在播放  长官
Tv's on in the background, sir.
而且播的是新闻  也就是说
And that is the news, which means
我可以用这个确认时间点
I can verify the time stamp using that.
很好
Okay.
干得好  各位
Good job, everyone.
继续努力
Keep it up.
不  这太简单了
No. Too easy.
看来我们又回到起点了
So it looks like we're back to square one, huh?
我可不会这么说
Well, I wouldn't say that.
我去查了被害人的医疗记录
I was looking into our vic's medical records--
我的一点点小调查
my little, uh, research project.
结果发现  他没有记录
Turns out, he has no records.
出生登记  医疗记录  学生成绩  什么都没有
Birth, medical, student transcripts, nothing--
詹姆斯·斯旺第一次出现
The first time James Swan pops up
是在他17岁  在纽约伊萨卡的
is when he was 17 when he was hospitalized
一起车祸医疗记录
for a car accident in Ithaca, New York.
为什么伊萨卡总是出现
Why does Ithaca keep coming up?
因为他是那里人
Because that's where he's from.
我查过急症室登记的地址
I checked the address in the E.R. records.
追踪到一个占地20英亩的公社
Traced it to a 20-acre compound
是一家世俗教化教堂的资产
owned by the church of Worldly Enlightenment.
各位  等一下
Whoa, guys, wait a second.
我听说过那地方  那是个邪教
I've heard about this place. It's a cult.
这就是为什么他没有接种任何疫苗
That's why he doesn't have any vaccinations
他也没有家的原因
and that's why he doesn't have a family.
他在邪教长大
He grew up in a cult.
唯一离开的方式就是逃走
The only way to leave was to escape.
那个公社高墙伫立
The compound is walled
邪教教俗又得严格遵守
and the cult practices strict obedience.
每个人的手臂上都有"服侍"的纹身
Everyone tattoos the word "Serve" on their forearm.
"服侍"
"Serve."
还记得詹姆斯的纹身吗
Remember James' tattoo?
"观察"
"Observe"?
他肯定是在他逃出来之后
He must have added the "O" and the "B"
又纹了O和B
sometime after he got out.
但当乐队在伊萨卡演出时  可能有人认出了他
But when the band played Ithaca, maybe somebody recognized him.
所以他担心
Which is why he was afraid
有人在跟踪他
that someone was following him.
詹姆斯有理由担心
James had reason to be afraid.
约翰·坎贝尔是邪教领袖
John Campbell, the cult's leader.
这家伙完全是个变态  还有暴力前科
The guy is a total psycho with a violent past.
在开创邪教骗局之前
He did ten years for murder
他因谋杀罪坐了十年牢
before starting the whole church scam.
知道坎贝尔现在在哪儿吗
Do we know where Campbell is now?
我可以告诉你他去过哪里
Well, I can tell you where he was.
我查了旅客名单
I checked passenger manifests...
给我看看
Let me see that.
所有附近的机场
For all the nearby airports.
他两天前抵达肯尼迪机场
He flew into J.F.K. two days ago.
是这样没错
Yeah.
等等  斯旺就是那天死的
Wait a second. That's the day Swan died.
就是说约翰·坎贝尔当时在城里
So John Campbell was in town
有好几天可以消磨[杀]
with a few days to kill.
发现双关没
See what I did there?
很棒  留下那段
That was good. Use that.
别留下我说的那句"发现双关没"
Don't use the part where I said, "See what I did there?"
这句剪掉  画面渐黑
Cut that out. Do a hard fade to black.
来段音乐
Musical sting.
找到坎贝尔了吗
Hey. Are we close on locating Campbell?
他的照片已经发到全市所有的巡逻车了
Well, his picture is out to all patrol cars citywide.
我还把他的照片发给了数据库所有的酒店
And I've sent his photograph to all the hotels in our database.
但问题是  他用化名
Yeah, but the trouble is, he uses aliases
以避开缉毒局的侦查
in order to stay off the D.E.A.'s radar.
缉毒局为什么对他感兴趣
Well, why's the D.E.A. interested?
他的邪教
The church of worldly enlightenment
不只是"友好"的邻家邪教
isn't just your friendly neighborhood cult.
它还是一个20英亩的大麻农场
It's also a 20-acre pot farm,
由300多人打理
run by the 300-plus members,
坎贝尔一人获利
all for Campbell's personal profit.
联调局怎么没把他们端了
Why don't the feds shut him down?
他们试过
They've tried.
但是因为宗教自由的原因
Something about freedom of religious expression.
还有什么邪教的信息
Can we get anything else on the cult
能帮我们找到他的
that can help us find him?
贝克特探长正在追查这条线  长官
Detective Beckett's working an angle right now, sir.
有发现吗
Any luck?
有  我刚跟"邪教观察"通了电话
Yeah, I just got off the phone with cultwatch,
他们会帮我们联系一个
and they're gonna hook us up with someone else
从坎贝尔的桎梏下逃脱的人
who escaped Campbell's compound.
我当时还小
I was a kid,
漂泊无依
drifting.
坎贝尔给我希望
Campbell promised me meaning,
给了我某种精神寄托
a spiritual focus.
作为回报  他夺走了一切
But in return, he took away everything.
卡洛琳你有没有对这些镜头感到不适
Uh, Caroline, are you worried about these cameras,
如果你想撤走的话
'cause if you want to have them gone--
不不
No. Mnh-mnh.
我想让世人知道他是怎样的一个禽兽
I want the world to know what a monster this man is.
詹姆斯·斯旺逃走之后  坎贝尔有什么反应
How did Campbell react when James Swan escaped?
他很愤怒
Oh, he was furious.
他原本很爱詹姆斯的
He used to love James.
所以他走之后背叛感特别强烈
That's why it was such a betrayal when he left.
我听说坎贝尔发誓要报复
I heard Campbell swear he'd get revenge,
不管需要多久
no matter how long it took.
伙计们  我有些线索
Hey, guys, I think I got something.
韦德马克酒店经理说
The manager of the Widmark Hotel
坎贝尔于两天前登记入住
said that Campbell checked in two days ago.
巡逻车派过去了没
Did you send a patrol car?
第二天早上他结账退房了
He checked out the next morning.
猜猜谁在他入住后就去见他了
But guess who came to visit him soon after he arrived there.
詹姆斯·斯旺
James Swan.
什么时候
When?
下午五点  斯旺被杀当晚
5:00 P.M. The same night that Swan was killed.
他杀了詹姆斯  我就知道
He killed James. I knew it.
詹姆斯在躲坎贝尔
James was running from Campbell.
为什么他还答应碰面
Why would he agree to meet with him?
为了换取自由
To buy his freedom.
我来猜猜  用两万五美元
Let me guess. For $25,000?
就是这样
That's right.
你知不知道我们去哪能找到坎贝尔
Do you have any idea where we could find Campbell now?
如果他在城里
If he is in town,
就可能在这个青旅
he might be at this youth hostel.
他在那里招新
He recruits there.
我就是在那里第一次见到他的
That's where I first met him.
好的  我们去会会他
All right. Let's go get him.
不好意思  你们在干吗  摄影机是干什么用的
Excuse me. What are you doing? What are these cameras for?
我们在找约翰·坎贝尔
We're looking for John Campbell.
不好意思  没有
Um... No, sorry.
这里没人叫这个名字
There's no one here by that name.
不好意思  那是私人房间
Uh, excuse me. That's a private room.
你不能进去  不好意思
And you can't go back there. Excuse me.
坎贝尔先生
Mr. Campbell.
关于詹姆斯·斯旺  我们有几个问题
We have a few questions about James Swan.
坎贝尔先生  午夜到凌晨两点你在哪里
Mr. Campbell, where were you between midnight and 2:00 A.M.
詹姆斯·斯旺被杀的当晚
The night that James Swan was killed?
我在酒店客房
I was in my hotel room.
有谁可以担保的吗
Can anyone vouch for that?
我那时正在冥想
Well, I was meditating.
独处是晚间仪式的一个重要部分
Solitude's a very important part of my evening ritual.
那就是没有
So that'd be a no.
那你来城里做什么
So what are you doing in town?
打理教派
Working for my church.
募集资金  主要是招新
Fund-raising, recruiting mostly.
"募集资金"
"Fund-raising"?
让詹姆斯·斯旺买自由
Interesting term for making James Swan
好意思用这么高端的词汇
pay you for his freedom.
我和詹姆斯见过面  这不是秘密
It's no secret that James and I had met.
但他并不需要买自由
But he certainly didn't need to buy his freedom.
我们都是自由人
We're all free.
坎贝尔先生  我们知道詹姆斯拿着两万五现金
Mr. Campbell, we know that James had 25 grand in cash
去见你
with him when he went to see you,
离开的时候钱就不在他身上了
and that he no longer had that money once he left.
詹姆斯可能是给教派捐钱
James may have made a donation to the church,
但我不会讨论那些事
but I make it a point not to discuss those matters.
那我们来谈一谈伊萨卡的事吧
Okay, so then why don't we discuss Ithaca?
大概一个月前  詹姆斯和他的乐队在那办了音乐会
About a month ago, James and his band had a concert there.
后来他说他担心
And he said that afterwards, he was concerned
有人跟踪他
that someone was coming after him.
我觉得那个人就是你
Now I think that that someone was you.
不好意思  不过我不知道詹姆斯上个月在城里
I'm sorry, but I had no idea James was in town last month.
我觉得这不准确
I don't think that's accurate.
我觉得是他跟你的教派一刀两断
I think that you're upset with him for cutting the cord
让你很不爽
with your church,
-然后你就开始跟踪他  -不是那样的
- and so you started tracking him. - That's not true.
他给你捐了钱  所以你就放过他了
He gave you a donation so that you would leave him alone.
不是那样的
That's not true.
但是还不够  对不对  你要报复
But that wasn't enough, was it? You wanted revenge.
-不  -你跟着他到了拖车里
- No. - So you followed him to his trailer...
够了
Enough.
然后你怒不可遏  杀了他
And then you killed him in a fit of rage!
够了
Enough!
如果你们有证据
Now if you have a solid case here,
就逮捕我
then arrest me.
不然  谈话到此为止
Otherwise, we're done.
你们要是再联系我
You contact me again,
我就告你们宗教迫害
and I will sue you for religious persecution.
长官  我们可以确定是坎贝尔做的
Sir, we're sure it was Campbell.
他有杀人动机
He had motive,
死者遇害当天他们还见过面
and he met with our victim the day that he died.
伊萨卡的事他也满口谎言
And he was lying through his teeth about Ithaca.
斯旺就是在那儿被他发现的
That's where Swan got on his radar.
你们能证明吗
Do you have any proof of that?
暂时不能
No, not yet,
我们在查乐队在伊萨卡期间的
but we're checking public records and police reports
公共记录和警方报告
from when the band was in Ithaca
看能不能跟坎贝尔联系起来
to see if there's a link to Campbell.
我相信缉毒局肯定希望
Well, I'm sure the D.E.A. will be delighted
你们能查到一些...
if you could help get some infor--
-不好意思  -嗯
- Excuse me. - Yeah.
我是盖茨
Gates.
不不  DVD就行了
No, no, no. DVDs will be fine.
非常感谢  米塔斯先生
Well, I appreciate it, Mr. Mitas.
好的
Okay.
是我们的导演
Our film director.
你们也知道  这个片子一定要
As you know, it's important that this project
表现分局的正面形象
reflects well on the precinct...
我相信一定会是这样
As I'm sure it will.
但刚刚我们几个警探确实在看性爱录像带
But we did have a number of officers watching a sex tape earlier.
但是
Still...
为确保我的手下
to ensure that the conduct of my people
尽可能符合最高标准
meets the highest possible standard,
米塔斯先生会把分局的带子都拿给我看
Mr. Mitas is sending over all the precinct footage for my review.
全部吗  长官
All of the footage, sir?
有问题吗  探长
Is there a problem, detective?
当然没有
Yeah, no, no. Of course not.
那就好
Okay.
她确认了
Well, she confirmed it.
这就是最后一块拼图了
Well, that's the missing piece.
去告诉贝克特吧
You should tell Beckett.
除非你想去
Unless you want to.
这个嘛
Well...
不了  是你查到的
Uh, no, no. You-- you brought it home.
但是整个邪教的事都是你查出来的
Nah, but you were the one who uncovered the whole cult thing.
是不是  是他让整个案子豁然开朗了
Right? I mean, this guy broke the whole case wide open.
对  但是是他
Yeah, but this guy was the guy
-查到了两万五的事  -对  但是
- who came up with the 25 grand, right? - Yeah, but--
喂  怒虎狂龙[讲一对警探的电影]
Hey, Tango and Cash.
你们到底有没有事要告诉我们
Is there something you guys want to tell us or not?
-你想来...  -不  你说吧
- Do you wanna... - Nah, go ahead.
好吧
All right.
我们在查死者在伊萨卡那晚的
Well, we were going over police records
警方报告
for the night that our vic was in Ithaca,
我们找到了别的东西
but we found something else.
约翰·坎贝尔报告了一起失踪人口
A missing persons report was filed by John Campbell
就在乐队离开的第二天
the day after the band left town.
邪教有人失踪了
Someone went missing from the cult?
对  一个叫巴克·库珀的人
Yeah, a guy named Buck Cooper.
我们跟"邪教观察"的联系人卡洛琳进行了核实
We checked with Caroline our Cultwatch contact.
发现巴克是斯旺当年在邪教时
It turns out that Buck was Swan's best friend
最好的朋友
from his days back in the cult.
这才是在伊萨卡发生的事
So that's what happened in--in Ithaca.
斯旺回公社是为解救朋友
I mean, Swan went back to the compound to break out his friend.
这才是坎贝尔去找他的真正原因
That's the real reason Campbell went after him.
那两万五不是给斯旺赎身
So the 25 grand wasn't for Swan's freedom.
而是给他的朋友
It was for his friend's.
他的证词能帮我们逮捕坎贝尔
This guy's testimony could help us nail Campbell.
我们一直在找他  但系统里没有他的资料
We've been looking for him, but he's not in the system.
但卡洛琳要给我们发张照片
But Caroline was supposed to send over a photo.
在这儿
There it is.
瞧啊  我们认识他
Boom. Check it out. We know that guy.
是我在犯罪现场跟他说过话的管理员
It's the roadie I talked to at the crime scene.
扳倒坎贝尔的关键
Well, the key to taking down Campbell
一直在我们眼皮底下
has been under our nose the whole time.
我知道我早就该出来说点什么
I know I should've said something earlier,
只是  詹姆斯让我小心行事
it's just, James told me to keep my head down,
然后他突然就死了
and then all of a sudden, he was dead.
我不知道该如何是好
And I didn't know what to do.
没事  巴克  你安全了
It's okay, Buck. You're safe now.
我欠他一条命
I owe that man my life,
现在我再也没机会报答他了
and now I'm never gonna get a chance to repay him.
其实  你或许有这个机会
Actually, you-- you might be able to.
你可以帮我们给坎贝尔定杀害詹姆斯的罪
You could help us nail Campbell for his death.
我真希望如此
I wish I could, ma'am.
天晓得那个人罪行累累
Lord knows, that man's done some terrible things.
问题是  他没有杀詹姆斯
The trouble is, killing James isn't one of 'em.
坎贝尔收下詹姆斯的钱时
When Campbell took the money from James,
他保证不会再来找我们麻烦
he promised not to bother us anymore.
我一定要听他亲口说
I needed to hear that myself.
我得看着他的眼睛
I needed to look him in the eyes.
詹姆斯被杀时你跟坎贝尔在一起
You were with Campbell when James was killed.
那么杀詹姆斯的不可能是坎贝尔
So then Campbell couldn't have killed James.
那是谁呢
But then who did?
真希望我知道
I wish I knew.
你在他拖车里的时候他对你说什么了吗
Did he say anything to you when you were in his trailer?
他说他要给我我应得的
He said that he was ready to make things right for me.
这话什么意思
Uh... Make things right?
他不是已经做到了吗
Didn't he already do that?
我也这么想
Yeah, I thought so.
詹姆斯帮我脱离邪教
James got me out of the cult.
帮我脱离坎贝尔的魔爪
James got me away from Campbell.
他还在乐队给我找了个工作
He even gave me a job in his band.
而我为他做过的  只是教他弹吉他
All I ever did for the guy was teach him how to play guitar.
你是他的老师
You were his teacher?
大部分人会说
Most guys will tell you
他们是自学的吉他
they learned to play guitar themselves,
但我有个导师
but I had a mentor, and...
他十分了不起
and the guy was incredible.
我永远达不到他的高度
You--much better than I'll ever be.
他怎么看乐队的
What's he think of the band?
我们很久没联络了
You know, we lost touch a ways back.
而我
And, uh...
有时候会想他现在怎么样了
Sometimes I wonder what he's up to.
明白了吗
Don't you see?
破解凶案所需的一切
Everything we need to solve this murder
都在这段视频中
is right there in that clip.
画面渐黑
Do a hard fade to black.
来段音乐
Musical sting.
巴克·库珀是詹姆斯·斯旺的音乐导师
Buck Cooper was James Swan's musical mentor, right?
所以  拍电影的问起詹姆斯过去的事
That's why, when the filmmaker asked James about his past,
他便想到了他的好朋友巴克·库珀
he automatically thought of his good friend Buck Cooper
和他欠他的人情
and how much he owed him.
所以他决定把巴克救出公社
Which is when he decided to rescue Buck from the compound
并带他一起巡演
and bring him on tour.
但他觉得让巴克做管理员不合适
But Buck as a roadie didn't seem fitting.
毕竟詹姆斯认为他是比自己
I mean, he was a better musician than James was,
还出色的音乐家
by James' own account.
这就是詹姆斯所谓的
That's what James meant
要给巴克他应得的
when he told Buck he wanted to make things right.
他是指要把巴克纳入乐队
He was talking about bringing Buck into the band.
没错
Exactly.
这才是他一直所说的方向的改变
That was the change in direction he kept talking about.
所以他告诉基斯这会对大家都好
It's why he told Keith it would be good for all of them,
因为巴克是个优秀的音乐家
because Buck is a great musician.
但是斯旺不是指所有人
Only Swan didn't really mean all of them,
因为吸纳了巴克  就得踢走一个人  谁呢
because if Buck was in, then someone else was out. But who?
埃斯波西托  你还留着斯旺让
Esposito, do you still have that sheet music
那个作曲写的曲子吗
that, uh, Swan commissioned from the songwriter?
就在这儿
It's right here.
太好了
Perfect.
研究一下这首歌
Working on the song a little.
要知道这些可不是什么普通的强力和弦
See, these aren't run-of-the-mill power chords.
真正的高手才弹得出来
You'd have to be pretty good to play th--
特别是这一段
Especially this part.
可以  我能弹
Yeah, I can play that.
很好  齐克
That's good news, Zeke.
因为我们正好拿来了你的低音吉他
Because we just so happen to have your bass guitar...
就在这
right here.
挡到脸了  放低一点
That's right in my face. A little lower.
谢了  LT
Thank you, L.T.
好吧  我承认  我弹不了
All right. Fine. I can't play it.
这也证明不了什么
That doesn't prove anything.
没错
No.
但这个可以
But this does.
这是我们在你的拖车里发现的一张干洗店票据
This is a dry cleaning ticket that we found in your trailer
昨天你刚把衣服送过去
for clothes that you dropped off yesterday.
上面还有詹姆斯·斯旺的血迹斑点
There are still flecks of James Swan's blood on them.
你知不知道在那些
Do you know what it's like
破烂的街头集市表演是什么滋味
to play all those crappy street fairs,
成天靠拉面过活
live on nothing but ramen noodles,
在面包车里睡14个月
sleep in a van for 14 months?
然后他居然在演出结束后打电话让我去他的房车
And then he calls me to his trailer after the show
告诉我我就这么出局了
and tells me that I'm out?
我承认
I admit,
我不是最棒的电吉他手  可
I might not be the world's greatest bass player, but--
别谦虚  你用吉他用得挺好
No, but you sure can handle a guitar.
得了吧  伙计  我不是故意想杀他的
Oh, come on, man! I didn't mean to kill him.
我们终于要成就一番事业了
We're finally about to hit it big,
英国音乐家  在披头士乐队担任过鼓手
后被乐队解雇  他从未得到令人满意的解释
结果他居然为了某个技术工
and he wants to "Pete Best" me
想让我成为彼德·贝斯特
for some roadie?!
我
I just--
我就发飙了
Ugh! I just lost it!
天呐
Ugh! God!
不
No.
要知道彼德·贝斯特是个鼓手
You know, Pete Best was a drummer.
我觉得斯图·萨特克里夫才是更恰当的比喻
I think Stu Sutcliffe would've been a more apt comparison.
真的很感谢你们为詹姆斯所做的一切
I really appreciate what you guys did for James.
我永远都不会忘记
And I'm always gonna appreciate that
我知道詹姆斯肯定也是
and... I know he does, too.
我
You know, I, uh...
有东西要给你
have something for you.
詹姆斯也会希望你能得到它
I think James would've wanted you to have it.
这一段没那么容易弹奏
The baseline is a little tricky,
不过我想对你来说应该不成问题
but I think you might be able to handle it.
齐克的事是真的吗
So it's true about Zeke?
嗯  恐怕是这样
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
这周可真惨啊
This has not been a good week.
我想告诉你  显而易见
I wanted to let you know, uh,
我们需要一个新贝斯手
we need a new bassist, obviously,
我正准备去见几个候选人
and I'm on my way to meet some guys right now,
不过我猜詹姆斯很看重你
but I guess James thought you were pretty good.
所以如果你想来试音的话
So if you want to come audition...
谢谢你  基斯  我会去的
Well, thanks, Keith. Yeah.
不客气  伙计
Yeah, man.
各位注意
Listen up, everyone.
我想在结案之际一如既往地
I, uh, just wanted to commend all of you
表扬一下
on a job well done,
大家的出色工作
as I always do at the end of every case.
您的表扬让人觉得抓获一个凶手的辛苦都值了
It's what makes catching a killer worthwhile.
但这说法很怪
Which is strange, because you think it would be
抓凶手就应该很满足的  但不是那样的
catching the killer, but no. It's...
长官
Uh, sir.
不好意思  长官
Uh, I'm sorry, sir,
关于那些您要的录像
about the, uh, the footage that you were reviewing.
您还在看吗
Are you still working on that?
没  我都看完了
No, I got through it.
贝克特警探  卡塞尔先生
In fact, Detective Beckett, Mr. Castle,
麻烦来一趟我办公室
my office, please.
我想你俩都很清楚为什么会被叫来
I'm sure you both know why you're here.
长官  请容我们解释
Sir, if you could just let us explain.
你们最好能给我说清楚
Oh, you'd better.
我可不觉得这事很有趣
Because I don't find this very funny.
我很自豪地说
I am proud to say that I have the, uh,
本局的罪案破获率是纽约市最高的
highest rate of solving crimes here in New York City.
这要大力感谢
That's due to-- in no small part--
所有优秀的警官和警探们
to my fine police officers and detectives,
辛勤工作
who take their work rather seriously.
他们住在自己的分局
Uh, they live here at the precinct.
全心全意为事业做出奉献
They dedicate their entire lives.
我们是一个团结的大家庭
Uh, we are a close-knit family.
你觉得这种行为
Would you call that behavior
在警察分局里是该有的吗
appropriate for a police precinct?
不
No.
没错
You're damn right.
你们到底想给我造成什么样公共关系危机才罢休
Just what kind of P.R. debacle are you trying to inflict on me?
对不起  长官
I'm sorry, sir.
这就是您想跟我们谈的录像内容吗
That's the, uh, footage that you're talking about?
-就这个吗  -就这个还不够吗
- That--that's it? - That's not enough?
难道还有别的什么我应该注意的
Is there something else I should be looking for?
是他们说少了的那部分视频吗
Like something on that tape they say is missing?
-不  不是  没有  我们  -不  不
- No. Not even-- no, nothing. We--  - No, no.
-不  没有  -我的上帝啊
- No, there's-- - Oh, for the love of...
外头这又是怎么回事
What kind of foolishness is going on out there?
所有的录像带我都要看
I need to view all of this tape.
明白没  所有的
You understand? All of it.
*想一想我们当初追逐的梦想*
*Think of all the dreams we've been chasing*
谢谢
Thank you.
*穿过阳光*
*Driving through the sunshine*
*穿过甘霖*
*Driving through the rain*
*回到路上*
*Back out on the road*
*重新出发*
*Again*
*上路吧  上路吧*
*Drive away, drive away*
*难道你听不见它的召唤吗*
*Can't you hear it calling?*
*行动吧  行动吧*
*Roll away, roll away*
*这是一个全新的黎明*
*It's a brand-new dawning*
*上路吧  上路吧*
*Drive away, drive away*
*难道你听不见它的召唤吗*
*Can't hear you it calling?*
*行动吧  行动吧*
*Roll away, roll away*
*这是一个全新的黎明*
*It's a brand-new day*
*任谁都能看见我的心跳*
*Anyone can see my heart's racing*
早告诉你们我会唱歌了
See, I told you I could sing.
-*然而现在等待已完结*  -是我教他的
*But now the wait is over* - I taught him how to do that.
*现在等待已完结  我们将面对整个世界*
*Now the wait is over and it's us against the world *
*每当我想到那些颓废的时光*
*When I think of all the time I've been wasting*
*颓废的时光*
*I've been wasting*
*凭己之力  我将永远*
*I never would've made it...*
来
Come on.
*实现不了*
*On my own*
我知道我不是特别
Look, I know I'm not the easiest person on the planet
好相处
to get to know,
不过你们真的很耐心
but you guys have been patient,
我有东西想让你们看看
and I've got something to show you.
这是个秘密
It's a secret.
其实吧  连卡塞尔都不知道
Actually, Castle doesn't even know about it.
我很喜欢去这个地方
It's--it's this place that I love to go to,
等你看到了
and once you see it,
我想你们一定会对我有更好的了解
I think you guys will understand me a whole lot better.
*我们所追逐的梦想*
*That we've been chasing, yeah *
*凭己之力  我将永远*
*I never would've made it*
来吧  一直往里走
Go ahead. All the way to the back.
*实现不了*
*On my own*
转过来
Turn.
*也永远无法回到家乡*
*I never would've made it home*